Guide to the Consumer Reports. Consumer Federation of America records, 1940-1994 RL.11813
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports. Consumer Federation of America records
1940-1994
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports (Firm)
RL.11813
8.0 Linear Feet
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. The Consumer Federation of America is an association of state and local non-profit consumer organizations, founded in 1967 in Washington, D.C. The Consumer Federation of America records include bylaws, clippings, correspondence, meeting minutes and other materials, newsletters, reports and other printed materials that relate primarily to the administrative activity of the organization. The records also include files of the organizational leadership, including Carol Tucker Foreman, Erma Angevine, Kathleen O'Reilly, and Robert McKuen. Other organizations represented in the records include the annual Consumer Assembly meeting and the National Association of Consumers. Topics and interest issues represented include banking, energy policy, insurance (automobile and life), prescription drug prices, and telecommunications deregulation and policy. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabeticaly.
Biographical / Historical
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. The Consumer Federation of America is an association of state and local non-profit consumer organizations, founded in 1967 in Washington, D.C.
Erma Angevine served as the first Executive Director (1968-1973). She was succeeded by Carol Tucker Foreman (1973-1977) and then by Kathleen O'Reilly (1977-1980). Robert McKuen served as the first president of the organization.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Consumer Reports. Consumer Federation of America records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2019.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Consumer Reports. Advocacy records
Consumer Reports Archives records
Consumer Reports. Frances Warne papers
Consumer Reports. Lynn Jordan papers
Consumer Reports. National Association of Consumers records
Consumer Reports. Sylvia Lane papers
Collection Overview
The Consumer Federation of America records include bylaws, clippings, correspondence, meeting minutes and other materials, newsletters, reports and other printed materials that relate primarily to the administrative activity of the organization. The records also include files of the organizational leadership, including Carol Tucker Foreman, Erma Angevine, Kathleen O'Reilly, and Robert McKuen. Other organizations represented in the records include the annual Consumer Assembly meeting and the National Association of Consumers. Topics and interest issues represented include banking, energy policy, insurance (automobile and life), prescription drug prices, and telecommunications deregulation and policy.
Consumer education; consumer protection; Energy policy; Insurance; Telecommunications; Banks and banking; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Consumer Federation of America; National Association of Consumers
- Consumer Federation of America Files, 1940-1994 and undated; 1
  - Achievements, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Annual awards dinner, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Annual meeting, 1968-1976; 11 folders (Box 1)
  - Annual meeting, 1973 (Box 13)
  - Annual report, 1975 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes: Contributions of members; financial statements; year in review
  - Annual reports, 1990-1994 (Box 2)
  - Banks, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Board meeting, 1968-1974; 11 folders (Box 2)
  - Budget and finance, 1968-1970 (Box 2)
  - Bylaws, 1969-1974; 3 folders (Box 2)
    Includes amended, proposed and revised bylaws
  - Bylaws and foundational documents, 1967-1969 (Box 2)
    Includes Bylaws; certificate of incorporation; membership application; resolutions preamble
  - Carol Tucker Foreman, 1975 (Box 2)
    Executive Director 1973-1977; file includes statements and testimony
  - Carol Tucker Foreman, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Certificate of incorporation; IRS tax exemption, 1967-1969 (Box 3)
  - CFA Consumer News and Comment newsletter, 1972-1974; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - CFA News newsletter, 1974-1994; 6 folders (Box 14)
  - CFA News newsletter advertisement, undated (Box 3)
  - CFA On the Record newsletter, 1972-1973; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Chairmen of standing committees, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Communications Committee, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Consumer Action newsletter, 1967-1968; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Consumer Action newsletter, 1990 (Box 14)
  - Consumer Assembly, 1966-1969; 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Consumer Assembly, 1966-1970; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Consumer Assembly, 1970-1992; 11 folders (Box 4)
  - Consumer Assembly--Clippings, 1967 (Box 14)
  - Consumer Credit Committee, 1971 (Box 4)
  - Consumer legislation, 1968-1970; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Consumers Information Committee, 1966-1968 (Box 4)
  - Consumers' National Federation (organized 1937), 1940-1956 (Box 4)
  - Consumers Union, 1968-1969 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1972; 4 folders (Box 4)
  - Credentials Committee, 1969-1971; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Documents (binder), 1972-1979; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Director's Manual update, 1973-1979 (Box 5)
  - Directory of state and local groups, 1973-1977; 3 folders (Box 5)
    Includes consumer groups, government and non-government organizations
  - Distinguished Service Awards dinner, 1971-1975; 5 folders (Box 5)
  - Don Willner, 1971 (Box 5)
    Don Willner was a Board member of CFA; Vice-President 1969-1970; named President of CFA 1971
  - Dues/Contributions, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Energy Policy Task Force, 1973-1975; 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Energy Policy Task Force, 1976-1977; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Erma Angevine--Memoranda and correspondence, 1968-1971; 5 folders (Box 6)
    Erma Angevine was first Executive Director of CFA, 1968-1973
  - Erma Angevine--Memoranda and correspondence, 1968 (Box 13)
  - Executive Committee, 1968-1976; 5 folders (Box 6)
  - Executive Director ballots, 1968 (Box 6)
  - Executive Director's report and statement relating to small business, 1973 (Box 6)
  - Fact sheet and other documents, 1972 (Box 6)
    Includes: Auditor's report; membership; policy resolutions
  - Finance, 1967-1971 (Box 6)
  - Finance and Budget Committee, 1970 (Box 6)
  - HEW conference with state consumer councils, 1968 (Box 7)
  - Howard Frazier, 1969-1970; 2 folders (Box 7)
    Howard Frazier served as president of CFA, succeeding Robert McKuen
  - Information files, 1975-1977; 3 folders (Box 7)
  - International Organization of Consumers' Unions (IOCU), 1968 (Box 7)
  - Kathleen O'Reilly, 1975-1977; 3 folders (Box 7)
    Kathleen O'Reilly served as Executive Director of CFA, 1977-1980
  - Legislation, 1968-1973; 5 folders (Box 7)
  - Legislation, 1971 (Box 13)
  - Lee Metcalf (Montana) statement in Congressional Record, 1968 (Box 13)
  - Life insurance report, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Mailing lists, 1968 (Box 7)
  - Meeting, 1968 (Box 7)
  - Membership lists, 1968 (Box 7)
  - Memo to CFA from Colston Warne on Consumers Union's efforts to build a consumer movement, 1971 (Box 7)
  - Memoranda and legislative action items, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Memoranda, statements, 1970-1994 (Box 8)
  - Minutes (binder), 1967-1972; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous, 1978-1979; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - National Advisory Committee, 1969 (Box 8)
  - National Association of Consumers (organized 1946), 1967 (Box 8)
  - National Association of Consumers (organized 1946)--Bylaws, 1955 (Box 13)
  - Natural Resources & Energy Committee, 1968 (Box 8)
  - News clippings, 1968-1969 (Box 8)
  - News from CFA newsletter, 1969-1974; 4 folders (Box 8)
  - News from CFA--Fact sheet, 1969 (Box 8)
  - Newsletter, 1972 (Box 8)
  - Nominating Committee, 1968-1970; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Not-for-profit corporation law, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Office space, 1970 (Box 8)
  - Officers and Board, 1968-1969 (Box 8)
  - Officers and Directors, 1968-1973 (Box 8)
  - Officers--State and local organizations, 1968-1970 (Box 8)
  - On the Record newsletter, 1972-1975 (Box 8)
  - Organization status, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Pamphlets, 1968-1977 (Box 9)
  - Policy recommendations, 1971 (Box 9)
  - Policy resolutions, 1973-1993; 12 folders (Box 9)
  - Policy statements, 1973 (Box 9)
  - Political platforms, 1968 (Box 10)
  - Prescription drug pricing report, 1972 (Box 10)
  - President's Committee on Consumer Interests, 1966; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Press releases, 1968; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Public relations, 1968 (Box 10)
  - Public statements, 1975-1976; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Publicity, 1967-1971; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Publicity, 1971 (Box 14)
  - Reports, 1973-1974; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Resolution Committee--Auto insurance, 1970-1971 (Box 10)
  - Resolutions preamble and policy statement, 1968-1969 (Box 10)
  - Review of CFA first five years, 1968-1973 (Box 10)
  - Robert J. McKuen, 1968-1969 (Box 10)
    Robert McKuen served as the first president of CFA
  - State-local consumer groups organizing project, 1975 (Box 11)
  - Statement of Carol Foreman before Platform Committee, Democratic National Convention, 1976 (Box 11)
  - Statements and testimonies, 1973 (Box 11)
  - Steering Committee on the creation of CFA, 1966-1969; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Telecommunications, 1986-1994 (Box 11)
  - Telephone legislation, 1983-1990; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Telephone legislation, 1983-1990 (Box 13)
  - Testimonies, 1975-1978; 4 folders (Box 11)
  - Testimonies, 1979 (Box 12)
  - Testing on S.825 (Voluntary Standards and Accreditation Act), 1977 (Box 12)
  - Trade policy statement, 1971 (Box 12)
  - Treasurer's report, 1969 (Box 12)
  - Year in review, 1974 (Box 12)
  - You've Got to Move newsletter, 1975-1976 (Box 12)